Supresh Mahajan

msupresh31@gmail.com ♦ +91 6005536576 ♦ ♠ Supr3sh ♦ 🛅 Supresh

Summary

An IT Professional with **3+** years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Successfully led a team of 3 deriving productivity and good results.

Professional Experience

Equilend Chandigarh

Senior Software Development Engineer

07/2024 - Present

- Enhanced CI/CD pipeline with Python scripts, Maven, and Jenkins; cut deployment time by **35**% and decreased manual intervention by **50**%, leading to more reliable and faster releases.
- Incorporated centralized config server backed up by Gerrit to improve CI/CD pipeline.
- Improved system performance by identifying and resolving memory and connection leaks and optimizing SQL queries.
- Trained a team of 3 members and led the team to automate the manual deployment and report generation processes

Stonewain Systems Chandigarh

Software Development Engineer

07/2022 - 06/2024

- Coordinated code reviews and best practices to ensure high-quality, maintainable codebase.
- Implemented a new microservice to store static data of 90+ tables in caches
- Successfully upgraded whole project from Java 8 to 11.
- Worked in a team to create a microservice which automates trade booking via pre-defined rules.
- Worked on docker. Switched from CentOS to RHEL after CentOS came to EOL (June 30, 2024)

Stonewain Systems Chandigarh

Software Development Engineer Intern

01/2022 - 06/2022

- Added bulk booking functionality via Rest API calls in the application using concepts of Spring AOP and Completable Future which improved performance by 56%
- Worked on shifting a Web application from Monolithic to microservice architecture to improve performance by 40%.
- Added Export to Excel functionality to the application using **Apache POI v5.2.3**.

EDUCATION

Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology

Patiala, Punjab

Bachelors of Engineering, Computer Science and Engineering

06/2018 - 06/2022

Secured a CGPA of 8.21 in Computer Engineering branch.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: ♦ Java 11 ♦ JavaScript ♦ HTML ♦ Oracle SQL ♦ C++ ♦ Python

Frameworks: \diamond Spring Boot \diamond Spring MVC \diamond Hibernate \diamond Rest APIs \diamond Struts \diamond Eh Cache

Tools: ♦ Maven ♦ Docker ♦ Jenkins ♦ Git/Gerrit ♦ Jira ♦ CI/CD

Operating Systems:

Linux

Windows